I promise you.
I'll make this right.
Dear Jonas,
you promised
to make everything right again.
I want you to know you will do that.
You must never lose hope
that there is a way out of this maze.
A way to save me...
and you.
But we both have to make sacrifices,
do unimaginable things,
to untie the knot at the end.
Each fate in this knot
is tied to the next.
A thread,
red like blood,
that connects all our deeds.
In light...
and in shadow.
Why is Adam doing this?
Why are you locking me up?
But the apocalypse
must take place.
You must let me die
so I can live.
We have to let some things go
before they find their way back to us.
We are a perfect match.
Never believe anything else.
LIGHT AND SHADOW
DAY OF THE APOCALYPSE
Martha?
Man, where were you?
Mom cried all night long.
Is everything okay?
Hey.
What happened?
What's wrong?
He was absolutely right.
Bartosz was right.
What he said in the forest...
about the end of the world.
The nuclear power plant. Today.
Bartosz's father is trying
to cover up an accident.
The barrels.
I know this sounds totally crazy, but...
the world's coming to an end today.
Have you got a screw loose?
When did you last sleep?
Are you even listening?
The...
I haven't got time for your psycho crap.
I don't know what's going on with you.
But it's not fair
to let Mom down like that.
She doesn't deserve that.
He had to die.
You two are wrong...
in his world.
And in ours.
I know what you're feeling.
But you'll learn to let him go.
Everything will run its course,
just as fate determined...
for our world...
and his.
Why did you lock me up?
You promised me there would be a way
to change everything...
so that the apocalypse doesn't happen.
You lied to me
just like my older self lied to me.
Sic Mundus.
Old Tannhaus.
He firmly believed
he was creating a paradise,
where we would all be free
from our destiny...
and free of pain.
A world beyond your world and my world.
But I...
have finally realized
what paradise really is.
Eternal darkness,
in which nothing exists.
But for that...
the apocalypse must happen.
In my world...
and in yours.
Jonas!
Let me out! Jonas!
6 HOURS UNTIL THE APOCALYPSE
Where are the barrels?
I want you to wait.
I don't care about that.
You do what I say, Obendorf.
Got it?
Dad? Is everything okay?
I know I said I'd stay home today,
but something came up.
I'm sorry.
It's all right.
I have to tell you something.
Someone is blackmailing me.
What?
With something...
that happened a very long time ago.
MURDER IN MARBURG
STILL UNSOLVED 33 YEARS LATER
Sometimes we make decisions in our lives
that we can never undo.
My name isn't Aleksander.
It's Boris.
Boris Niewald.
But it was an accident.
You have to believe me.
I am not a murderer.
What about Mom?
Did Mom know about this?
Your mother is the best thing
that ever happened to me.
She saved me from all that.
And I never even told her the truth.
Bartosz.
I'm sorry.
Charlotte.
May I come in for a second?
Thanks.
I need to speak to Ulrich. Is he here?
No. He's still in the shower.
Could I maybe wait? It's important.
How are you?
Okay.
And at home? Is everything fine?
Now you listen to me...
Ulrich belongs to me.
And that's not going to change.
Charlotte.
-What are you doing here?
-I just wanted to show you something.
Drop by with Peter sometime.
We can all go out together.
While I still can.
-Are you done in the bathroom?
-Of course.
-What are you doing here?
-Your cell was off.
Don't ever do this again.
Never come here uninvited.
The microscopic examinations
of the two pennies are in.
And...
And?
And what?
WINDEN POLICE
EVIDENCE
This is the penny I found in the bunker.
And this is the penny Helge had on him.
At first I thought it must be a mistake,
that the photos were labeled incorrectly.
But this here,
this little groove.
It is exactly identical.
I don't know how,
but it's one and the same coin.
But this one here, Helge has had it
as long as I've known him.
I know it makes no sense at all,
but...
But?
It's as if the penny...
had somehow traveled through time.
-Where's Helge now?
-Still in pre-trial custody.
Ulrich!
Oh, you startled me.
Where were you?
Did you cut your hair?
What happened?
Do you believe in fate?
I don't know.
No.
I believe we take our lives
into our own hands.
That we decide which path we take.
I know I...
I'm probably the last person
you want to talk to, but...
if you do want to...
I'm here.
Your dad and I...
A lot of things may be different now...
but that doesn't necessarily mean
it's bad.
No, it doesn't.
Are you going somewhere?
I promised someone
I'd take care of something.
WINDEN NUCLEAR POWER PLANT
GOD PARTICLE
FOLLOW THE SIGNAL
Stop!
Jonas.
You're alive.
I killed him.
Why is he still alive in his world?
The switch point...
at the junction in the loop of time.
The moment
that allows things to run
in one direction or the other.
You bring him to our world,
or you don't.
A line that meets itself again in a loop.
Two possible paths:
along the outer edge of the line,
or along the inner edge of the line.
And yet it is the same line.
Two overlapping realities.
On one of these paths, he dies.
On the other, he doesn't.
Both possibilities recur in the loop
again and again.
One triggers the other.
Quantum entanglement.
Adam has tried to sever
this entanglement for the past 33 years,
so what is growing inside you
will never come to be.
But it is impossible.
Our worlds
cannot be separated from one another.
Every step Jonas takes is guided by us.
He cannot escape his fate.
What is this?
This was left over...
after the catastrophe.
The God Particle.
And this here?
What is this?
I've seen what it will become,
in the future.
There's no way back now.
The cave collapsed. There's nothing left.
The passage no longer exists.
But this here...
if I find out how it works, I can go back.
Then I can save them. Martha and Mikkel.
I can save them all.
How did you even find me?
How did you know I was here?
The device.
-The matter it needs--
-The device. Do you still have it?
Where is it?
It doesn't work.
Maybe it all had to happen this way first,
for things to change next time.
The substance in the device,
you and I brought it
into the passage again.
We changed the variables of the equation.
-Maybe it will work next time.
-I don't have time to wait 33 years!
Am I supposed to lie to myself again
to have things happen the same way?
But this time I'll be on the other side
of the bunker door?
Why didn't she say anything?
Your older self.
She knew Martha would die.
How she'd die.
Why should I trust you?
The matter in the nuclear power plant.
I know what it is.
I can help you save Martha,
to save them all.
3 HOURS UNTIL THE APOCALYPSE
Bartosz?
Martha?
Can I come in?
Yes.
33 years ago, there was an accident
at the nuclear power plant.
Somehow the accident caused
some strange substance to form.
And your father helped
cover everything up.
The whole time,
that stuff has been in the caves.
It's all connected.
The substance...
it triggers it.
Today.
We have to talk to him.
Triggers what?
The apocalypse.
POLICE
IDENTITY UNKNOWN
The time of death must have been
just before the body was found.
Is it possible
that he's been dead for a long time?
That his body had been preserved somehow?
Preserved?
What do you mean "preserved"?
Everything okay?
The scar on his chin...
Ulrich?
The boy in the bunker.
You said you killed him.
But you didn't mean him.
You meant Mads.
The boy from the bunker
looks just like Mads.
How can that be?
She... she said I had to do it.
Who?
Do what?
Send him to the future.
To fill the gaps.
The pennies.
What does this mean?
-I have to stop him.
-Stop who?
Stop who?
You.
You can go.
And this Jonas guy is dead now?
And you killed him.
Well, not you, but...
some other you?
I was there.
In the future.
Nothing's left.
Nothing.
It all has something to do
with your father.
He can't be allowed to open the barrels.
Bartosz.
Please.
Charlotte, it's Aleksander.
I...
Can you come to the nuclear power plant?
I want to show you something.
Come on out!
Adam's waiting for you.
Stop.
Take it off!
-What?
-Your clothing.
Take it all off.
Why are you doing as he says?
We, the chosen few, must fill the gaps.
So you can find your way here,
and Adam his...
and we'll finally find salvation.
We have waited
a long time for this moment.
You know what to do.
1 HOUR UNTIL THE APOCALYPSE
What do you think it means?
The birds? The light?
The boy in the bunker?
Martha is losing it.
She thinks
the apocalypse will happen today.
If we die today, then together.
Together.
What's this about?
It's better if you see it yourself.
Tick, tock.
Tick...
tock.
Charlotte, it's me.
Listen, the stuff with the pennies...
I know it sounds crazy, but the same thing
happened with the body in the bunker.
Have them run a DNA test.
I don't know how, but...
the boy in the bunker,
he's my brother. It's Mads.
Call me back when you get this.
Who are you?
Can't you guess that?
Magnus?
You're from the future.
But not from yours.
What's going on?
They lied to you.
Your older selves.
They don't want to prevent the apocalypse.
They're the ones
who are responsible for it happening.
But there is a way to change everything.
But you have to choose our world...
and trust him;
Jonas.
Jonas is alive?
In our world.
And he knows where the origin is.
But before that, you must save Jonas
from the apocalypse in his world,
and bring him into your world.
You're all out of your minds.
You can't stop
what's happening here, but...
if you come with us,
you can prevent it...
another time.
What is that?
Martha, what's this all about?
Martha?
You have to come with us.
-Come where?
-He doesn't belong with us.
He belongs with the others.
They will save him.
I'm sorry.
Martha, wait!
It's time.
Adam has moved
each of his pieces into position.
It's time
that we do the same.
This knot has given us all life,
and we are its keepers.
In both worlds.
He'll never be able
to untie the knot.
In all these years, he hasn't understood
how everything is really connected.
How everything ends and begins.
Not only in our world,
but also in his.
We are...
destiny.
We build the walls...
of this labyrinth.
Each of us shapes the paths
and extends their hand.
Bartosz, you must save yourself
to save our lives.
Claudia, you must guide yourself
to be our eyes in Adam's world.
Egon, you must create your past
to preserve the family tree.
Noah...
you bring love
to make everything new.
Every darkness is followed by light.
With every death comes a life.
You brought me into your world.
You promised me I could change it.
Why are you doing this?
Where are the others?
Where did you send them?
They are all fulfilling their destinies.
Magnus and Franziska.
Charlotte and Elisabeth.
Silja and Agnes.
They're perpetuating the cycle,
so that you and I can be here now.
What's that supposed to mean?
That we've come to the end.
What's growing inside you,
the origin,
must die.
But it can't be killed by normal means.
It's born of both worlds,
and the energy of both worlds is necessary
to destroy it.
The apocalypse in my world,
and the apocalypse in your world.
This here is the end.
A machine that not only crosses time,
but also space.
It focuses the energy of both apocalypses
onto this one point.
Your son only exists
because the matter exists.
And now he will die through the matter,
and all of us with him.
None of this...
will exist anymore.
Both worlds will extinguish one another.
Absolute annihilation.
You're insane.
There is no hope.
No salvation.
No paradise.
We're wrong,
you and I...
in your world
and in mine.
Jonas.
Jonas!
Jonas, please don't do it.
Don't. Jonas, please!
Jonas!
Jonas, please!
No!
Jonas!
No, no!
The beginning is the end,
and the end is the beginning.
Every connection in one world
must also be closed in the other world.
Everything is connected.
In light
and in shadow.
POLICE
TANNHAUS
MACHINERY FACTORY
VOLUME CONTROL ROOM
LET THERE BE LIGHT
No!
Subtitle translation by Nathan Fritz