I remember.
I remember everything.
CROSSROADS
What are you doing here?
The boy we found in the forest.
What's going to happen to him now?
If you don't figure out who he is
he'll be cremated
and buried in an anonymous grave.
How long has he been dead?
It's all in my report.
When you found him,
ten hours, more or less.
Is it possible that he...
Purely hypothetically,
is it possible he's been dead for longer,
and was somehow preserved?
Preserved?
You mean, like frozen?
If so there would be traces in the tissue.
I would've noticed.
Frozen steak isn't like fresh steak.
-So that's a no.
-Nope. Not that I'm aware of.
How long of a preservation period
are we talking about?
-Thirty-three years.
-Thirty-three years?
The way he looks?
That's pretty much impossible.
MISSING
What day is it today?
-Pardon?
-What day is it today?
November 9th.
I know this sounds crazy...
but what year?
'86.
Thanks.
Wait.
Are you looking for someone?
Yes.
A friend.
Michael Kahnwald.
Never heard of him.
-Ines Kahnwald's son?
-The nurse?
She doesn't have any kids.
Do you know where I can find Ines?
At the hospital maybe.
Well, see you.
Regina, you stupid four-eyes!
We got the power plant shift schedule
for the night Mads disappeared.
I want you to interview them
so we can check their routes and times.
-Maybe we'll find something.
-Can't someone else do that?
I'm working on the case with his brother.
A rape charge.
I mean, we never did consider
whether he may be involved
in his brother's disappearance.
Yes.
Egon.
This isn't the 1950s.
We don't base investigations on hunches,
but on evidence.
You have three months until retirement.
Then you can do whatever you want.
Until then, you do what I want.
33 YEARS?
'86.
'86. '86.
I'm just saying
the ground shook yesterday.
I know this isn't an earthquake zone,
but the ground shook.
-The search warrant for the power plant.
-I have to go.
You have my number
in case you think of anything.
Should I tell Ulrich?
No. Why would anyone talk to me?
Egon.
Helge. You're the one I wanted to see.
Can I help you?
It's about the missing Nielsen boy.
The night he disappeared,
you were on your shift, right?
Yes.
Martin wants to document and corroborate
the routes and times
of everyone who was near here that night.
I have to do my rounds
and check the blocks now.
Okay.
Let's arrange a time
for you to come to the station.
-Day after tomorrow.
-Tuesday.
Is 10:30 okay?
That works.
Sorry for the trouble.
It's no trouble.
I just didn't see anything.
What I mean is...
Everything was totally normal.
Your shift ended at six?
Yes, that's when the night shift starts.
Did you take your car?
I took the state road.
Were you heading somewhere else?
Because you took the state road instead.
Isn't the forest road shorter?
Yeah.
I just picked something up for my father.
See you Tuesday.
Helge?
One more question.
Did you see his brother anywhere that day?
The older Nielsen boy, Ulrich.
Nope.
Till Tuesday.
POLICE DAY PLANNER 1986
INTERVIEW: JANA NIELSEN
INTERVIEW: HELGE DOPPLER
WHY NOT FOREST ROAD?
"10:30, interview with Helge Doppler.
Why not forest road?"
SEARCH WARRANT
Can I help you?
Shouldn't you be in school?
I'm sick.
Well, you look just fine to me.
I hurt my arm. I'm headed to the hospital.
Get in. I'll drive you there.
"Bosch, Teller, Voigt,
Fleischer, Brandt... Doppler, Helge.
27."
CASE: NIELSEN, MADS
STATEMENT: FUCHS, DOREEN
STATEMENT: DOPPLER, HELGE
Yes?
Did you know
that in 1986 your father-in-law
was to be interviewed
in my brother's case?
No.
I went through all the files.
Helge was supposed to be questioned
on Tuesday, November 11, 1986.
Exactly 33 years ago,
from the day after tomorrow.
But there is no statement. He didn't show.
There's just a note.
-"Why not forest road?"
-So you think Helge abducted Mads in 1986?
And now Mikkel and the other boys
33 years later?
-Where is he now?
- In the nursing home. Ulrich!
He's 75 years old. He has dementia.
And the evening Mikkel disappeared,
Helge was with me.
But the evening before Yasin vanished,
Wöller found Helge in the forest.
And took him back to the nursing home.
Somehow this all has to do with Mads.
-You're barking up the wrong tree.
- Maybe.
But maybe not.
What's your name?
Jonas.
And why didn't you have
your parents drive you?
My mom is at work.
My dad's dead.
Where does your mother work?
At the power plant.
The power plant has changed Winden.
This place used to look different.
What's that there?
Earphones.
Those aren't earphones.
You just put them in your ears.
Now I've seen it all.
It's a shortcut.
Well, here we are.
Wait.
Among you teenagers,
is...
Is Satanism a thing right now?
No idea.
No, I don't know. I don't think so.
Call your mom to pick you up.
It's best not to walk
through the forest alone right now.
Thanks.
I'm looking for Ines Kahnwald.
-She was just outside with the boy.
-What boy?
What do you want Ines for?
I'm visiting and I locked myself out.
Ines didn't mention a visitor.
Are you related?
Yes, you could say that.
Maybe she's still out back.
-Otherwise, I'll tell her when I see her.
-No, I don't want to be any trouble.
Mr. Doppler?
My name is Ulrich Nielsen.
I'm a police officer.
Don't be scared.
I just want to ask you a few questions.
In 1986, a boy from Winden vanished,
Mads Nielsen.
Do you remember?
You were summoned to the station for
questioning, but there's no transcript.
What does "why not forest road" mean?
-He is...
-What does "why not forest road" mean?
-It's him!
-What does it mean?
-What are you doing here?
-It was him!
-I'm a cop. I want to ask a few questions.
-I know you!
What? What did you say?
-You have to go!
-What? Why were you summoned?
-I can change it. I can change the past.
-I need help!
And the future.
What did you say?
-What did you say? Where is Mikkel?
-Let him go!
Where is my son? Where is Mikkel?
Let me go! Tell me where my son is!
Let me go!
-Let me go! Don't touch me!
-I can change it.
I can change the past.
And the future.
Tick-tock.
Look! I managed to find another one.
How little we understand of the world.
Is this real?
Or am I crazy, just like my father?
Do you even exist?
Or are you the hallucination of a lunatic?
You're not crazy, neither was your father.
Sometimes it's hard for us
to grasp things that go against
all we are conditioned to believe.
How did people feel the first time
they were told the Earth was round?
-Yes, it is. It's totally insane.
-And if it's not?
How can that be?
Is there a breach in time in the cave?
So Mikkel hangs out here
until he becomes my father?
Even if you don't want to believe it,
that is your father.
That means...
that Ulrich is my grandfather and...
Martha is your aunt.
That's bullshit.
I'm taking him back
and putting this right.
Don't you get it?
If you take Mikkel back, you'll be
meddling in the course of events.
Your father will never meet your mother,
they won't fall in love or get married.
And you won't be born!
If you take him back now,
you'll be erasing your own existence.
The role you play in all of this
is much bigger than you think.
But every decision for something
is a decision against something else.
A life for a life.
What will you decide?
What's the big idea?
First the power plant, now this.
-You know that I have to suspend you.
-Things are going on that make no sense.
Maybe I'm going crazy.
The dead boy.
The boy we found in the forest.
Helge has something to do with it all.
I know you want
to find Mikkel at all costs.
But the end doesn't justify all means.
I should have taken you off this
on day one.
Helge said he can change
the past and the future.
-What's that mean? Why did he say that?
-Helge has dementia.
He can't even tie his own shoes anymore.
He's surely not responsible
for the disappearance of three children.
-He doesn't have the strength.
-Maybe he's not alone.
Go home.
"Why not forest road?"
What does that mean?
Egon Tiedemann wanted to ask him that.
"Why not forest road?"
I don't know who said it,
but Ulrich didn't rape me.
-You don't have to lie for him.
-But I'm not lying.
I wanted it.
We both wanted it. He didn't force me.
And your face? What happened there?
I fell down.
It has nothing to do with it.
Someone saw you.
-Saw how he hurt you.
-That can't be.
Then that person's lying.
-Who said that anyway?
-I'm not allowed to say that.
The only important thing is
that you know
that Ulrich can't harm you right now.
And that he will be punished
for what he did to you.
Ulrich didn't do anything.
If anything, I pressured him into it.
I asked him to get condoms.
But he'd never hurt me.
He would never do that.
Never.
I've been suspended.
Where are the kids?
No idea.
I'm sorry, Katharina.
I'm here now.
You haven't been here for a long time now.
What do you mean?
As long as I've known you,
you've wanted out of Winden.
Were you ever really happy?
What are you talking about?
Of course I was happy.
Weren't you?
I know, Ulrich.
What do you know?
About Hannah and you.
Did she tell you?
Does that matter?
Katharina.
I think I've known it all along.
I just didn't want to see it.
I can explain.
Please don't, Ulrich.
Oh, yeah.
Your mother called a while ago.
Our son has disappeared
and all she talks about is Mads.
And I thought my family
was the one full of assholes.
Hello.
If you take him back now,
you'll be erasing your own existence.
But every decision for something
is a decision against something else.
FOR MOTHER'S DAY 1986
Would you want to know,
after all these years?
What?
If he's dead.
No.
I have always held on
to the hope that he's alive.
Your father wanted the grave.
He thought it would help me
find some closure.
But there's no body in it.
For 33 years
I've been imagining that he's alive.
Free.
And happy.
You can never give up hope.
There's as much light out there
as there is darkness.
Don't forget that.
Katharina said
you wanted to tell me something.
One week before Mads...
I didn't tell the police this back then.
I didn't even remember.
I saw something.
In front of the house, across the way,
a priest was arguing with a man.
I don't know what about.
But I found it odd that a priest
would be arguing like that.
And this morning, I saw the same man.
The priest?
No, not the priest. The other man.
It was the same man.
I...
I know that because he had something
on his ear, it was...
It was scarred or disfigured.
But he wasn't a single day older.
He looked exactly like he did
33 years ago.
I know that sounds crazy.
But it was the same man.
Am I interrupting?
You wanted to know if the cave system
goes under the forest road by your cabin.
Not all of it is mapped out.
But at least parts of it extend
under the south part of the forest road.
What's with the cabin?
Is there anything in particular there?
No. Nothing.
Thanks.
Sure thing.
Charlotte?
Did you know that your father was supposed
to be questioned by the police in 1986?
No, I...
-Why do you ask?
-The cabin on the forest road.
Why did Helge keep it
after all that happened to him there?
Did he even use it?
Did he rent it out?
Why are you asking?
When was the first time you were there?
Was it already in 1986?
I don't know why you want to know that.
Did your father live in the cabin in '86?
I don't know.
Maybe.
I came to Winden in 1987.
I didn't know about the cabin then.
- That was after Helge's accident.
-When was that?
- Where are you now?
-When was the accident?
November 12th, 1986.
So three days from today.
Come home.
The kids have barely seen you in days.
They're worried.
And so am I.
-I have to go.
- Charlotte...
Dad, the question isn't how,
the question is when.
Boy, you startled me.
Where were you?
What's wrong?
Do you believe in fate?
I... I don't know.
Maybe it's my fate that men leave me.
I think Dad loved you very much.
DO NOT OPEN BEFORE NOVEMBER 4,
10:13 P.M.
A JOURNEY THROUGH TIME
This is Charlotte Doppler. I'll call back.
Charlotte,
the question isn't
who abducted the children, but when.
I was right, Helge Doppler.
Not now, but in 1986.
Call me back immediately
when you get this.
NOVEMBER 5, 1953
NOVEMBER 9, 1953
Subtitle translation by
Nathan Fritz, Peter Rigney