Mom?
Mads?
Who are you?
Where are my parents?
-Who are you?
-Do you know where he is?
-Do you know where Mads is?
-You're hurting me.
What are you doing here?
Say something.
When is he coming back?
PAST AND PRESENT
Ines, can you do
the night shift today too?
Mrs. Schüttler's daughter has a fever
and I have to take Benni to soccer.
-Since you have no...
-No family.
-That's not what I meant.
-It's not a problem.
Thanks.
And please, don't tell Dr. Reimann?
-Mum's the word.
-Thanks.
The news.
November 5, 1986.
After the mysterious disappearance
of an 11-year-old boy
in Winden over four weeks ago,
criticism of local investigators
is growing ever louder.
The circumstances
of the case are puzzling.
Despite an extensive search,
Winden Police have been unable to find
a single piece of useful evidence.
The police are therefore continuing to ask
for the public's assistance.
- The chemical plant fire in Switzerland...
-Tiedemann.
- ...is doing damage to local waterways.
-Where?
- Toxic chemicals are entering the Rhine...
-I'm on my way.
In times like these...
one must...
face one's own fears.
Because the future...
the future belongs to the bold.
Not to the doubters,
those forever stuck in the past.
Would you take a look at yourself?
You can't go to school like this.
Sometimes I think you have no idea
what it is I do.
Food, clothes, fencing classes.
Who pays for all of that?
And you can't even bother
combing your hair.
Look at yourself.
You look like a limp dishrag.
Hey, Regina, I'm talking to you.
This is a huge deal for me,
and I won't let you spoil it.
The board's decision to entrust this post
to a woman for the first time...
MISSING
MADS NIELSEN
It's awesome.
-Know what the song's about?
-No.
A man who kidnaps a girl
and takes her to the forest,
just because she's wearing red lipstick.
In the end he kills her.
That's heavy.
My dad says lipstick
is only for prostitutes.
Anyway, I like Nino D'Angelo
way more than Falco.
Hannah, you're as square as they come.
Come on, Katharina. Don't be so nasty.
What are you looking at?
Weren't you at Ulrich's place earlier?
Are you new here?
I...
I'm looking for my mom.
This isn't kindergarten.
She's the principal here.
Mr. Hubert?
He may be a fag,
but he's certainly not a woman.
Isn't this Winden?
Aren't you a bit young to drop acid?
You guys got history now?
-Morning, Claudia.
-Morning.
-Your first day as boss.
-Yes.
My dad told me
the board voted unanimously for you.
I wanted...
-Congratulations.
-Thanks.
I always knew
something would become of you.
-Oh, Helge.
-And I have...
A present for you.
It's a book.
Thanks.
Well, I'm running late.
I have to get going.
We're all behind you, Cl...
I came just before six to feed the animals
and found this.
Maybe a wolf?
No bite marks. Nothing.
Poisoned?
Yesterday they were lively as can be.
First the thing with the boy,
and now this.
Such things didn't use to happen here.
Who would just kill 33 sheep?
"Be on guard! Be alert!
You do not know
when that time will come."
The Gospel of Mark, 13:33.
Didn't know you were a churchgoer.
The parish has a new priest.
A good man.
Mrs. Tiedemann.
Mrs. Tiedemann,
Tronte Nielsen from the paper is here,
for the interview.
And here are the figures
from 1986 and 1985, as you requested.
They weren't easy to get a hold of.
And congratulations again.
I still can't believe
we have a woman as boss.
Are you sure these are the right figures?
Yes.
REPORT:
33 DEAD SHEEP
What are you doing here?
I...
I'm looking for my dad.
What's his name?
Ulrich Nielsen.
Ulrich Nielsen? The Ulrich Nielsen?
-Doesn't he work here?
-No.
And I'm certain he never will.
Oh, so this is a joke?
Was this Ulrich's dumb idea?
Did he do this?
Did Ulrich do this?
-What's your name?
-Mikkel.
-Last name?
-Nielsen.
I'm Ulrich's son.
Now tell me your parents' real names
and I'll take you home.
What's the date?
5th of November.
What year?
1986.
Tiedemann.
I have an injured boy here.
Can one of you come pick him up?
Thanks.
Someone will be coming
to pick you up and take care of that.
In the meantime I'll take care of Ulrich.
He won't hurt you again.
I promise.
An interview? Are you serious, Tronte?
People are interested.
A woman taking charge
of the nuclear power plant.
That's progressive, even for the '80s.
I have no time for this today.
Make a new appointment with my secretary.
Hey!
I miss you.
I thought we talked about this.
You can't just leave me hanging like this.
Claudia, I need you!
I'm going stir crazy at home.
-Jana loses it more and more and I...
-I want you to go now.
Tonight?
Please.
Maybe.
The number you have dialed
is not in service.
Please call information.
MISSING PERSON'S REPORT
MADS NIELSEN
WINDEN BOY (12)
VANISHES WITHOUT A TRACE
MADS NIELSEN (12) MISSING
SINCE LAST WEEK
Hello.
I'm Nurse Ines.
But you can just call me Ines.
I'll take you to the hospital now.
We'll take a look at your arm, okay?
Then I'll bring you home safe and sound.
Hello?
Hello!
What are you doing here?
Why do you listen to such stuff?
The boy you sent...
-Do you think that's funny?
-What boy?
Don't think you'll get away with this.
-Have we been drinking again?
-Beg your pardon?
-I asked if you've been drinking again?
-Who do you think you are?
I want us to find your brother
as badly as you do.
-What's this?
-A hoof. That's obvious.
-Did you do that on the pasture?
-What pasture?
Did you kill the sheep?
If you'd stop drinking your brain to mush,
then Mads might be back by now.
Mr. Tiedemann?
-The door was open.
-Because of Mads.
He forgot his key.
Chief Inspector Tiedemann
wants to update you on the investigation.
They've got new findings.
Exactly. You have nothing.
Now kindly piss off!
Everything's in working order.
How did this happen?
And you still won't tell us your name?
Nurse Ines will bandage you up, okay?
Then you can go back home.
RECORD OF PATIENT ADMISSION
Don't cry.
Don't cry. Everything will be okay.
Bernd? I have to talk to you.
Were you trying to slip this past me?
I said I need to know
if there are skeletons in the closet.
There are things that are worth knowing
and things worth not knowing,
because you can't change them anyway.
What is this?
These are nothing like
the reported figures. Here.
And here.
Everywhere.
It's been like that for three months now.
Do you know
what has changed since Chernobyl?
People have lost faith.
In us, in nuclear power.
They saw the images.
And they can't
get them out of their heads.
But fear is the worst enemy of progress.
So?
How many people around here
rely on this plant for their livelihood?
-We have 612 employees, excluding...
-Everyone!
And when you take over this job tomorrow,
you'll be taking on responsibility
for the nuclear power plant,
but you'll also be taking responsibility
for the entire town.
And now tell me
I wasn't wrong about you.
All the more reason
for me to know just what this means.
And? Everything A-okay with your daughter?
Yes, everything's A-okay.
It's a big deal.
A woman taking charge of the power plant.
Sure it is.
-And your granddaughter?
-Regina?
She's good too.
So were they poisoned?
Hardly.
All signs point to sudden cardiac arrest.
-Cardiac arrest?
-Yes.
All 33?
It's common with sheep.
They're very sensitive creatures.
If a few start to panic,
the entire herd freaks out.
It's a vicious cycle.
They just drop dead.
Like flies.
-And what could cause such a panic?
-All kinds of things.
A person?
A single person?
Unless he's Freddy Krueger,
he'd have his work cut out for him.
Was one of the sheep...
I mean, was one of them missing a hoof?
No.
They're all as God created them.
Do you know anything about Satanists?
You think Satanists did this?
As far as I know,
they make a big show of it all.
You'd find traces on the pasture.
Very strange.
Look here.
The eardrums are ruptured.
On both sides.
Strange.
Coming to our party this weekend?
My wife's making Yugoslavian meatballs.
Spicy as hell, but also tasty as hell.
What we know is a drop,
what we don't know
is an ocean.
Won't you tell me
your name and where you live?
Don't you want to go home?
If something happened at home...
you can stay here for now.
If you want to talk, I'm here.
I'm on the night shift too.
Here, something to read.
I come from the future.
What did you say?
Mom?
Hi, it's Mom.
If you're hearing this, heat up a pizza.
I'm coming later.
I have something to take care of.
-Hey, Hannah!
-Hey, Ulrich.
Is this the Apocalypse?
A bit disappointing.
I imagined it being louder.
More glaring.
If the world ended today,
and everything started anew,
what would you wish for?
Easy.
A world without Winden.
To a world without Winden.
I don't think Winden
is going to give up that easily.
Well, maybe next time.
A JOURNEY THROUGH TIME
Hello?
Hello!
Help!
Hello?
Anybody there?
Mikkel?
Subtitle translation
by Nathan Fritz, Peter Rigney