[quiet, aroused breathing]
[disturbing music]
[threatening music]
[gasps, panting]
["Goodbye" by Apparat plays]
♪ Fold out your hands ♪
♪ Give me a sign ♪
♪ Put down your lies ♪
♪ Lay down next to me ♪
♪ Don't listen when I scream ♪
♪ Bury your doubts and fall asleep ♪
♪ For neither ever ♪
♪ Nor never ♪
♪ Goodbye ♪
♪ Neither ever ♪
♪ Nor never ♪
♪ Goodbye ♪
♪ Neither ever ♪
♪ Nor never ♪
♪ Goodbye ♪
[gasps]
Isn't it peculiar
that we feel the most repulsion
for the very people
who are most similar to ourselves?
I just want to know how to get home.
[tense music]
Get dressed.
[dismal music]
JUNE 25, 2020
TWO DAYS UNTIL THE APOCALYPSE
[door opens]
[quick footsteps descending stairs]
Wait a minute.
There's something you need to see.
-We have to go.
-It's probably best if you sit down.
Maybe some other time.
We really have to go.
[sighs]
I...
I've got to tell you this.
It sounds insane, but I need to know
what you think about it.
[Martha] What the hell?
For months you haven't even spoken to us.
And now you want to know what we think?
Look around you.
We're the kids here,
but you've behaved like one for months!
I mean, fuck, Mom, think you're
the only one who deals with this shit?
But it's not you alone!
No.
Even if you want to talk now,
we don't need it.
[door closes]
[Aleksander] Why is he so interested
in the power plant?
I want you to find someone
at the Federal Police who knows Clausen.
Find out what he's really doing here.
Call me as soon as you're able
to figure this out.
Bartosz isn't here.
His bed wasn't slept in.
He wasn't here all last night.
-He's probably at Martha's.
-They broke up.
They could've gotten back together.
Did you try calling?
No one's answering.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Say everything's okay.
Everything's okay.
[unsettling music]
Doing all right, Inspector?
FORMER WINDEN CHIEF INSPECTOR
EGON TIEDEMANN
FOUND DEAD ON JUNE 26, 1987
[mysterious music]
CIRCUMSTANCES
SURROUNDING HIS DEATH STILL UNCLEAR
[knock at door]
Ms. Tiedemann.
The French delegation.
They're all waiting. I think you better...
Reschedule.
What?
-Reschedule.
-[stammering] But I can't just...
Why am I here?
A man
lives three lives.
The first one ends
with the loss of naïveté,
the second, with the loss of innocence
and the third...
with the loss of life itself.
It's inevitable
that we go through all three stages.
You turn into your older self.
And your older self...
will turn into what you see here.
I don't have time for all this shit here.
I have to get back now, to my time!
I know what will happen.
I've seen all the graves.
You have lots of time.
This is the year 1921.
Strictly speaking, you have 99 years left.
[eerie music]
[door opens]
So, a fresh snack.
[door closes]
People can say whatever they want.
This Reagan, he's a great guy.
The Olympics, on both sides of Berlin.
I'd say that's visionary.
I recorded his speech.
It was on last night.
[grunts]
[suspenseful music]
[old Egon Tiedemann]
You haven't been here in a long time.
I just wanted to see
how you were getting along.
It's all right.
Claudia...
You know that I'm quite proud.
Of all your accomplishments.
And your mother would be too.
I have to go.
The actual reason I came is...
I think you should live with us.
You wouldn't have to be so alone.
And Regina would be happy
to see more of you.
How about tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
You're acting as if I'm inches from death.
Think it over, please.
All right?
[door closes]
[gloomy music]
[loud knocking at door]
[loud knocking]
[door opens
[Hannah] Katharina!
What do you want?
[door closes]
Is he here?
Jonas.
He disappeared.
I have no idea where he is.
You said you saw Mikkel.
You were there.
How do I get there?
He has a sort of...
apparatus.
I guess you'd call it a...
time machine.
[chuckles softly]
A time machine.
And do you know how this thing works?
It wouldn't help even if I did.
He took it with him.
[Katharina] He was always there.
Right in front of me.
I just can't take in the fact
that you slept with my husband and my son.
I guess you always wanted
everything that was mine.
You're like a parasite.
Did Ulrich ever tell you
that he loved you?
In the end, he would always choose us.
[knocking]
[door opens]
[Clausen] Good afternoon.
-[Hannah] Hello.
-You missed your appointment yesterday.
[door closes]
[Hannah] Oh, I'm sorry.
I guess I forgot about it.
One would think a mother whose child
is missing wouldn't forget that.
Mrs. Nielsen.
You're the last person
I expected to see here.
But since you're already here...
have you ever seen this man?
No, I haven't.
[dismal music]
[Clausen] How about you?
You recognize this person?
No.
[glass breaking]
[tense music]
[melancholy music]
[young Jonas] Do you know
everything that's going to happen?
[Adam] I know when wars begin and end...
what discoveries science makes
in the next few years...
what shares to invest in.
But I don't know
what my counterpart will do...
as long as I haven't seen his future.
But you know my future.
You know what I'm going to do.
I am your future.
There must be a way to change everything.
So that things happen differently.
A loophole.
It took me 66 years
to discover a way out of all this.
A way to finally leave this hell.
[Clausen] I've been here about a week,
and I get the impression
no one here is telling the truth.
Everyone's hiding something.
What I don't know is
whether everyone is hiding the same thing,
or if they all have their own skeletons
in the closet respectively.
Is he paying you?
Aleksander Tiedemann.
I don't quite follow.
You worked for him as a physiotherapist.
You've stopped now, correct?
Mm-hmm.
And yet he still wires you
the same amount every month.
One would normally require a service
in return. What exactly is the service?
What you don't understand
is that we support each other.
We stick together here.
My son has disappeared.
Aleksander helps out with money.
That's all.
[Clausen] Nothing
beats a good neighborhood.
It's quite remarkable
that Mrs. Nielsen is
also so understanding.
Uh, maybe that's how it is
in small towns like this.
You don't just share secrets...
you also share your bed.
[eerie music]
-[Charlotte] I want to know what you know.
-[older Jonas] All right.
Who is Noah?
[older Jonas] He is one of them.
A traveler.
He's Adam's puppet.
He killed the children.
Mads, Erik, Yasin.
It seems like all of this
is somehow tied to me.
Do you know who my parents are?
No.
But I knew your grandfather.
He's not my real grandfather.
I just grew up with him.
Did he know all of this?
Is he one of them?
A traveler?
He's just a pawn, like most of us.
Claudia,
she used him,
like she used me, Peter and the others.
She had him build this.
[unlocking machine]
You know what will happen,
in the future?
Yes.
[low moan]
[Magnus] What is this?
Want another night, maybe?
Bartosz, look at us.
What are we doing here?
-Why won't you tell us what's going on?
-I would if I could.
I'm not allowed to.
Even if I told you,
you wouldn't believe me.
Why wouldn't we?
Humans can survive three days
without any fluids or nourishment.
[Bartosz panting]
[Bartosz] You're crazy.
You can't do this.
Are you going
to leave me here to die or what?
[quietly] Hey, Martha.
Martha, please. Martha!
You can't do this, Martha! Martha!
Okay.
It's a time machine.
What?
Are you kidding me?
I told you
you wouldn't believe it.
Come on. We're leaving.
No. Wait.
Then show us how it works.
I need a phone.
-There's no reception.
-That doesn't matter.
It just needs to search for the signal.
That's all.
[quiet whizzing and rattling]
[suspenseful music]
[crackling]
Come closer.
[mysterious music]
[Claudia] The incident last summer...
You said it was the result of a reaction
in the volume control system.
I checked the data.
Everything was normal.
So?
What really happened?
I knew you'd always refuse to let this go.
After the incident,
I had a sample taken and analyzed.
What you see there are the results.
These values... They don't make sense.
I thought so too, initially.
So I had them run the tests another time.
The results were always the same.
If the data is correct, then...
-is this what I think it is?
-It's possible.
It corresponds in several ways
with the calculations
of Englert, Brout and Higgs.
In '64.
Ah, but not entirely.
The God Particle.
The particle
that gives all things the mass they have.
This is just sensational.
If this data is correct,
we have to make it available to everyone.
As I've told you before,
sometimes it's all right
to let sleeping dogs lie. Hmm?
If we make it public people will want
to know how we discovered it.
The nuclear plant
is my only legacy.
Do what you want with the data,
but just keep my name
and the plant out of it.
At least so long as I'm alive.
Are you all right?
Can I help you?
Hello, Ines.
Ina, hello.
We're out of iodine again.
Ah.
-Have you heard?
-Hmm?
A patient escaped from the nuthouse.
In the '50s he supposedly killed two kids
and beat another one half to death.
He's on his last legs now,
but they say we should stay on alert.
[dismal music]
Thank you.
[quiet, mysterious music]
You look familiar somehow.
I've waited 33 years
for this moment to get here.
[mysterious music]
"The question isn't how...
it is when."
That's what you said.
Do you recall?
[Ulrich weeps]
Papa.
[Jonas] In the future
there's a prophecy about a new world.
That Sic Mundus
will lead mankind to paradise.
Is that this?
A religion?
We're the exact antithesis of that.
We've declared war on time.
God is our antagonist.
We are creating a new world.
Without time.
Without God.
How is that?
In short, the god mankind
has prayed to for thousands of years
the god that everything is bound with,
this god exists as nothing
other than time itself.
Not a thinking, acting entity.
A physical principle
with which you can no more negotiate
than you could with your own fate.
God...
is time.
And time is not compassionate.
The instant we're born
our lives start to trickle away,
like the sand in this hourglass.
Death is always inevitable.
Our destiny
is nothing but the connection
of cause and effect.
In light,
in shadow.
[store bell jingling]
[clocks ticking]
[threatening music]
Charlotte.
What do you want from me?
-I am Noah.
-I know who you are.
You've been killing the children.
I can't make you
change your mind about me.
But...
perhaps one day you will understand
that I only did all this to finally put
a stop to everything once and for all.
So you won't be taken from me again.
Just like your mother was.
[ominous music]
They didn't think you had much of a chance
when you were born.
You were premature, tiny.
But you wanted to live.
You were so strong.
Your little hand grabbed my finger
and wouldn't let go of it.
Stop it!
This isn't possible.
Your mother took this picture.
I promised her I'd bring you back.
I kept searching for you.
But you were here all along.
-[gasps softly]
-Adam knew it was you.
He knew it the whole time.
He is preparing for what's to come.
I've read all of the last notes.
The nuclear plant, Jonas.
It's all going to happen again,
the apocalypse.
In two days.
But I know now...
what I have to do.
I have to end Adam
so that everyone else can live.
Not just those in the bunker.
[Charlotte] Who is my mother?
She loved you very much.
She still loves you.
[ominous music]
[crying softly]
[door opens]
[door closes]
What happened here?
[Franziska] The chair is gone.
-[Magnus] What's going on?
-[Bartosz] I didn't believe it at first.
But then he told me about things
that were going to happen.
And they all eventually did.
That...
you and Jonas would kiss each other.
He told me about it before you did it.
That my mother would get cancer.
That Jonas would vanish.
Who told you this stuff?
-Noah.
-Noah?
The priest? Tall, blue eyes?
-You know him?
-I don't, but Elisabeth does.
Okay, what is all this?
Noah said it's about a war.
About controlling time.
That my grandmother is involved.
-That Jonas would return and that...
-[Martha] Jonas?
Jonas will return?
Yes, he's a part of this war.
[scoffs]
[Magnus] I'm going home.
Do you trust me?
[tense music]
-[door unlocks]
-[Ines] Michael?
Michael!
Egon, it's Ines.
I know this sounds strange, but I got home
and Michael isn't here and...
The man who broke out
of the psychiatric clinic. I...
What man broke out of the clinic?
It was all over the radio.
Do you remember
the kids from the construction site
in 1953?
That man, that's who broke out.
I'll get in touch with the station.
I might know where they're headed.
I'll pick you up.
[line disconnects]
[threatening music]
[sirens blare in the distance]
[tires squeal]
-[gunshots]
-[policeman] Stop! Don't move!
-[Ines] Michael!
-Let go of the boy!
-Let him go!
-No!
-Get on the ground!
-Michael!
-You don't understand!
-[policeman] On the ground!
-This is my son!
-I said let go of the boy right now!
-[Ulrich] Mikkel!
-Michael!
Mikkel, I... I'll come back.
I'll take you home.
I promise!
I promise.
It's all your fault.
It always has been.
I swear, next time I will kill you!
[policeman] Let's go!
[Ulrich] Mikkel!
Mikkel!
[oppressive music]
[Adam] Mikkel,
Michael, our father,
is just a small part of a knot
that is infinitely greater
and more convoluted.
The entire universe
is nothing but a giant knot
from which there is no escape.
If that's the case,
if everything is tied forever
in this knot,
if nothing can change... then haven't you
already had this conversation?
And asked that very question.
All my life I was convinced that...
this moment here
could never be repeated this way.
I would never be able to say the words
that my older self said to me back then.
Because I couldn't understand
how I could ever want
what he wanted.
Now,
66 years later, I understand.
There are moments that change us forever.
There is pain you never forget.
But there is also a way...
that leads out of all this gruesome,
senseless futility.
But if that's correct,
if there is an escape,
why is everything happening again,
why have you changed nothing?
Every development
is built on its predecessor.
First there is the wheel,
then the automobile.
I cannot be me
without having been you first.
You have seen the passage yourself,
the bunker,
the chair,
the device,
the thing in the future.
But that's not the end of the chain.
Thank you for taking the time.
I'd like you...
to test this for me.
And not a word.
To anybody.
What is this?
If it's what I think it is,
it will change our understanding
of the entire world forever.
[atmospheric music]
PRESERVE CREATION
GAIN THE FUTURE
[cars approaching]
Hey. Hey, stop the car!
Those are my children!
Magnus!
Martha!
Believe me now?
[door unlocking]
[door opens]
[door closes]
You came back.
Where'd you go?
[Jonas] Did this
ever mean anything to you?
Did you love Dad at all?
I know you had an affair with Ulrich.
If you could choose
between Papa and Ulrich...
In all this mess, I really thought
you were the only person I could trust.
I fucked up everything. I know that.
Maybe you've always done that.
Jonas.
You need no one.
You only need yourself.
["May the Angels" by Alev Lenz plays]
♪ May the angels bow down for you ♪
♪ And lay their feathers ♪
♪ Beneath your feet ♪
♪ May the angels fill your emptiness ♪
♪ Guide and lighten ♪
♪ Up your path ♪
♪ But I can't ♪
♪ And I won't ♪
♪ May the angels ♪
♪ Show you their boundless love ♪
♪ Like the mother ♪
♪ Not the wife ♪
♪ May the angels ♪
♪ Soothe and ease your pain ♪
♪ May the angels instill a will ♪
♪ But I can't ♪
♪ And I won't ♪
♪ I can't ♪
♪ I won't ♪
♪ I'm leaving ♪
♪ I'm healing ♪
♪ I'm growing ♪
♪ I'm loving ♪
♪ 'Cause you won't ♪
♪ And you can't ♪
[women vocalizing]
[song fades]
It's not the same
as the one in the future.
Maybe it's something like its twin.
[whirring and bubbling]
It's a section of the infinite.
It penetrates everything.
People have given it
all sorts of names over the centuries.
Ether,
dark matter, Higgs field.
How was it created?
In the future,
by the catastrophe in two days
that you so dearly want to prevent.
This one
was created by us.
It is the continuation
of technical evolution.
And...
it will be the end of this knot.
This one will send you exactly to the day
that you want to travel to.
It will break the 33-year cycle.
That's why I'm here.
That's what you want from me.
The way to stop this all from happening
is for me to stop the very beginning.
That is right.
The question is, when is the beginning?
And what sacrifice must we make?
The 20th of June, 2019.
The day before it happened.
Before my dad committed suicide.
Before it all went to chaos.
If you can prevent him
from taking his own life,
then nothing that follows will occur.
Mikkel
won't travel back.
You...
I...
will never be born.
But everyone else will live.
Martha will live.
[whirring, bubbling]
[crackling]
[buzzing]
[rumbling]
If you succeed,
we will reorder the whole world.
[whirring and banging]
[atmospheric music]