What is reality?
And is there only one of them?
Or do several realities coexist?
To help explain, Erwin Schroedinger
devised an extremely interesting
thought experiment.
Schroedinger's cat.
A cat is locked in a steel chamber
with a tiny amount
of radioactive substance,
a Geiger counter,
a vial of poison, and a hammer.
As soon as a radioactive atom decays
inside the steel chamber,
the Geiger counter releases the hammer,
which smashes the vial of poison.
The cat is dead.
However,
due to the wave characteristics
in the quantum world,
the atom has both decayed and not decayed,
until our own observation
forces it into a definitive state.
until the instant we look and see,
we don't know
if the cat is dead or alive.
It exists in two superposed states.
The properties "dead"
and "alive"
therefore exist simultaneously
in the microcosm.
But what if the simultaneous existence
of life and death
also applied to the macrocosmic world?
I'll make this right.
Could two different realities
potentially exist side by side?
Could we manage to split time
and allow it run
in two opposing directions?
And by doing so, allow the cat
to simultaneously exist in both states,
dead and alive?
And, if so,
how many different realities...
could exist side by side?
Martha!
Wait!
You can't go in there.
Bartosz?
-What are you doing here?
-Adam and the others lied to you.
He doesn't want to help you.
He's going to kill you.
In the future.
He doesn't want to stop the apocalypse.
Everyone will die.
Not because of you, but because of him.
I know what the origin is.
And how it's all connected.
Please.
I can show you.
You've got to trust me.
IN BETWEEN TIME
It's hard for people to accept death.
TANNHAUS FAMILY: NOVEMBER 8, 1971
MAREK, SONJA, CHARLOTTE
We hold on tightly to things
that are long gone.
CHARLOTTE
MAY 30, 1971
We long in vain
for a way to turn back time.
A way to reverse death.
But if time is relative
and nothing is really ever in the past,
and the simultaneous overlapping
of different realities is possible,
shouldn't it then be possible
to bring back something
that was believed to be dead long ago
and to create a new reality
in which what is dead lives again?
If our life is defined as that
which lies between birth and death,
then it exists there in infinite versions.
Could we succeed in cheating death
by finding a way
to bring back life?
There, between time.
FOR CHARLOTTE
Tell me about paradise.
Paradise...
is free
of pain and suffering.
Everything we've ever done...
is forgotten there.
Any pain...
we've ever felt...
is erased.
And...
all the dead...
live.
Adam will keep his promise.
The passage will open.
What do you want?
You've been promising us
there's a way out of here for ages.
That we can stop the apocalypse.
But you still don't know
how the portal works.
It will work.
I saw it work.
In the future.
And then what?
When are you finally going
to tell us the truth?
You don't want to go back.
You don't want
to stop the apocalypse at all.
This is bigger than us.
Bigger than the apocalypse.
If the portal works,
we can use it to find the origin.
The one moment that started all this.
And when we've found it, we'll destroy it.
And everything that arises from it.
That is paradise.
Paradise?
We've been stuck here for two years.
Two fucking years!
I don't want your fucking paradise.
I just want out of here.
Hello?
I... didn't mean to startle you.
Sometimes I think
it'll never stop raining.
I'm...
Silja.
Bartosz.
We can start
a new series of experiments tomorrow.
I know we've been trying for a long time,
but it will work.
Jonas.
You can't lose hope.
I can't do this anymore.
What are you doing here?
Are you following me?
You promised me something.
Adam promised me something.
You said the apocalypse must happen.
So that we can be saved.
So that all of us will be saved.
You can't die.
You can't take your own life.
Because your older self already exists.
Time won't allow it.
No matter what you try...
something...
or someone...
will always stop you from doing it.
Elisabeth and I,
we found the passage.
You must keep your promise.
It will open again.
And then you will...
Then Adam will...
lead us to paradise.
He said we will become friends.
Before you betray me.
Yes! Good.
Once more.
Yes! Yes!
It's a boy.
What will you name him?
Hanno.
Fate is playing a cruel game with us.
Yet we will always believe there is
a way to turn the tide in our favor.
If only we want it badly enough.
A person is able to pursue a goal,
no matter how unattainable it may seem,
over the course of an entire lifetime.
No resistance, no obstacle is great enough
to stop one from pursuing one's will.
Is this stubbornness in our striving
not that which distinguishes us
from animals,
which know only short-lived desire?
And isn't all progress, through all ages,
not the product
of this unquenchable act of will?
No matter what motivates our will,
it will guide us on our path.
We will only be able to let go
when we have finally attained our goal
once and for all.
Why do you think it's not working?
Maybe Claudia doesn't want it to work.
Why do you even trust her?
Why did you trust him?
Adam?
He lied to you.
There is no paradise.
There's no world other than this one.
I know you think I will become him.
But I won't.
The portal will work, I've seen it.
In the future.
Everything repeats itself.
But if I can travel back,
I can change everything.
My older self tried it before,
but this time, everything's different.
I've changed the components
in the passage.
This time, it'll work.
She told you that?
Claudia?
What do you really know about her?
She sometimes disappears for days.
How does she know
all the things she knows?
She said
not everything that's here belongs here.
What did she mean by that?
Come inside.
Claudia's hiding something from us.
We can't trust her.
I hope you know that.
He still doesn't suspect anything?
No.
He has no idea you
or the other world exists.
You must continue
to guide him on his path.
The matter, it must not work yet.
You uphold the knot in your world,
and I'll uphold it in mine.
Wait.
All these past few years,
the things Eva said I had to do...
Does she know everything that happens?
I was wondering.
Have you ever met her?
Who?
My older self.
No.
I still remember exactly what she said.
"If everything goes right...
Regina will live."
I've thought about that all these years.
I just can't believe
that by that she meant
her suffering was to repeat
over and over forever.
There must be a way to untie the knot...
without destroying all life in it.
A way for Regina to live.
Really live.
I think
neither Eva nor Adam know that path.
But I'll find it.
In my world or yours.
Don't...
You didn't bring Claudia with you?
Noah is watching her.
We have to be careful.
You must give this to Claudia.
And she must give it to Tannhaus.
She understands
why it's necessary?
Why everything has to happen again?
You have to be strong now, Hanno.
For your father too.
Silja...
Bartosz, we tried everything.
She wanted to name her Agnes.
Tell me about paradise.
Paradise...
is free
of pain and suffering.
Everything we've ever done...
is forgotten there.
The passage will open.
And then...
we will be there.
You,
me...
and Charlotte.
Where is she?
Charlotte?
Where is Charlotte?
All these years,
I wondered what he meant by that.
That we'd be friends before you betray me.
Where's Claudia?
Does she have Charlotte? Did you help her?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Where is she?
Where's Charlotte?
I don't know.
I wish you all the suffering in the world.
I will find her.
I will bring her back.
I promise I will.
A man can do what he wills,
but he cannot will what he wills.
All the paths we take in our lives,
every decision that we make,
is guided by that which we desire
deep inside ourselves.
We cannot fight that desire.
It determines every one of our deeds,
no matter how grave and unimaginable
they seem.
Hannah?
Silja?
I...
I'm looking for Jonas.
Yes.
He has changed.
Traveling has left its mark on him.
Jonas?
This is my daughter.
Silja.
She's your sister.
How did you find us?
A few days ago...
there was this old woman.
She just showed up on our doorstep.
Eva.
She said...
she knew where you were.
And that you were looking for me.
You're right.
It's all my fault.
I ruined everything.
But now I'm here.
I'm here, Jonas.
Bartosz.
Prepare the chamber for them.
What are you doing?
Silja.
She doesn't belong here.
What's that supposed to mean?
"She doesn't belong here"?
All the pieces have to be in position.
She's in the wrong place.
So are you.
Mom.
I want to show you a secret.
But we'll let your mom sleep, okay?
Come on.
I...
I have traveled far.
I need a place to sleep.
Hanno?
Prepare the chamber for this gentleman.
I was wondering when you'd come.
I know you think I lied to you.
That I took Charlotte away from you.
But I didn't.
You were right.
Claudia...
she lied to all of us.
The book...
Do you have it with you?
Are the last pages missing?
You must find the last pages.
They will lead you to Charlotte
and to your final destination.
You will find your paradise.
And Helge...
will help you do so.
Everything in life happens in cycles.
Sunset
is followed by sunrise,
over and over.
But this time...
it will be the last cycle.
Are you ready, Noah?
The matter,
it can finally be stabilized.
Everything must happen again
in exactly the same way.
You have to lead your younger self
down the same path.
He must not act differently.
MISSING
MIKKEL NIELSEN
You have to set the course,
no matter how hard that may seem.
But you'll finally be able
to change everything.
WINDEN WELCOMES ITS NEW MINISTER
The device...
He'll repair it.
A JOURNEY THROUGH TIME
You must destroy the passage,
and the knot with it.
You'll succeed this time.
Jonas...
You must never lose hope.
POLICE
Weeks ago, in the small town of Winden,
a 15-year-old boy
disappeared mysteriously.
Residents are now alarmed
after a second child has gone missing.
Eleven-year-old Mikkel
has been missing for two days.
Report any information
you may have to the Winden police.
Hello, Claudia.
Don't you want to get in?
You have to stop Adam.
FOLLOW THE SIGNAL
Have we met?
I'm sorry.
You are the white devil.
JUNE 27, 2020
BEGINNING OF THE LAST CYCLE
Charlotte?
No, this can't be true.
Mom.
Jonas.
I've looked for you all these years.
You are not my father.
Regina?
I'm so sorry.
You used me.
There is no man without guilt.
None of them deserve
a place in your paradise.
Jonas?
And so the circle closes.
What about Martha?
Why did you bring me here?
They're the only ones who'll save us.
Save us?
Everything that's happened is their fault.
No.
They are the light.
What do you want from me?
Isn't it peculiar...
that one feels the greatest aversion
towards the people
who are most similar to oneself?
I'm not like you.
You and I have nothing in common.
My whole life, I believed
that this moment
could never repeat itself.
That I could never do
what my older self had done.
Because I couldn't understand
how I could ever want what she wanted.
But now...
66 years later, I understand.
Some pain is never forgotten.
It brands us for our entire life.
You and I...
we share that pain.
We bear the same scars.
A memento.
So you never forget
which side you really belong on.
You may not understand yet,
but choosing us is choosing life.
Choosing Adam is choosing death.
No!
This can't be.
Hello, Jonas.
Subtitle translation by Nathan Fritz